This now brings us to an extremely important property of LMS called the context window that I want to
이제 LMS의 아주 중요한 속성을 살펴보죠 컨텍스트 창이라고 하는데 자세히
explain clearly.
설명할게요
The context window is telling you the total number of tokens that an LLM can examine at any one point
컨텍스트 창은 토큰의 총수를 알려줍니다 LLM이 어느 시점에서든 살펴볼 수 있는 것이죠
when it's trying to generate the next token, which is its big job.
다음 토큰을 생성하려고 할 때요
Its job is to generate the most likely next token, given a number of tokens that have come before and
가장 가능성이 높은 다음 토큰을 생성하는 일을 합니다 이전에 온 토큰의 개수와 조사할 수
the number of tokens that it can examine, that it can look at in order to make that prediction is limited
있는 토큰의 개수를 부여받습니다 그 예측을 하기 위해 살펴볼 수 있는 토큰은
by the context window, which is limited itself by the size, the number of parameters in the LLM and
컨텍스트 창에 의해 제한됩니다 컨텍스트 창은 크기, LLM의 매개 변수의 수, 그리고
the the the way that it's been constructed, the architecture of the LLM.
그것이 만들어진 방식과 LLM의 구조에 의해 제한되죠
So what does that mean?
그게 무슨 뜻이죠?
Is that just saying that's how many input tokens that you can have for it to make an output token.
출력 토큰을 생성하기 위해 입력 토큰을 얼마나 가질 수 있는지에 대한 것인가요?
Kind of.
그런 셈이죠
But it's worth clarifying what that really means in practice.
하지만 실생활에서 그 의미를 명확히 할 필요가 있어요
You remember at the beginning we had when we were when we were first working with our first LLM, our
우리가 처음 작업했던 첫 번째 LLM, 첫 번째 OpenAI 호출을 기억하시나요?
first OpenAI call, we had a system prompt and then a user prompt.
시스템 프롬프트와 사용자 프롬프트가 있었죠
This was all part of our input to the LLM, and it was then predicting the most likely next token in
모두 LLM에 대한 입력의 일부로 입력 프롬프트에서 가장 유력한 다음 토큰을 예측했죠
We passed in a website and it was then and we said, now summarize.
웹사이트에서 전달한 다음 요약해 보라고 했죠
And then the most likely next token was a summary of that website.
다음 토큰은 해당 웹사이트의 요약이고요
Now when you have a chat with something like ChatGPT, you pass in some input and it then produces some
챗GPT와 같은 것과 채팅을 할 때 입력값을 입력하면 입력값이 출력되고
output, and then you might ask another question.
그러면 다른 질문을 하게 되죠
Now in practice, it appears that ChatGPT seems to have some kind of a memory of what you're talking
실제로 챗GPT는 당신이 하는 말을 일종의 메모리로 기억하는 것 같아요
about.
토론의 맥락이 유지되지만 이건 일종의 환상이죠
It's a bit of a conjuring trick.
일종의 비트를 쓰는 거죠
What's really happening is that every single time that you talk to ChatGPT the entire conversation so
실제로 일어난 일은 챗GPT와 대화할 때마다 지금까지의 대화 전체에서
far, the user prompts the inputs and its responses are passed in again, as are the long prompt.
사용자가 입력을 프롬프트하면 그 응답은 다시 넘겨집니다 긴 프롬프트처럼요
And then it ends with okay, what is most likely to come next given all of this conversation so far?
지금까지의 대화를 종합해 보면 다음 단계는 무엇일까?로 끝나죠
So what the context window is telling you is that this is the total amount of tokens.
컨텍스트 창이 말하는 것은 이것이 토큰의 총량이라는 것이죠
The total amount of information, including perhaps the original prompt the system prompt.
원본 프롬프트를 포함한 총 정보량이죠 시스템 프롬프트요
The user prompt the question you made its response.
사용자가 반응을 유도하죠
Your next follow on question, its response to that, your follow on question then and now.
그에 대한 반응과 과거와 현재에 대한 반응이죠
It's having to generate new contacts, new contacts, new tokens to come at the end of this, this long
새 연락처, 새 연락처, 새 토큰을 생성해야 합니다 이 끝에서 오기 위해서요
chain of backwards and forwards.
앞뒤로 긴 사슬이죠
So the context window then is the total of all of the conversations so far, the inputs and the subsequent
컨텍스트 창은 지금까지의 모든 대화와 입력, 그리고 다음 토큰을 예측할
conversation up until the next token that it's predicting.
때까지의 대화들을 모두 담은 것이죠
So it's it's it's important to have that in mind when you're first starting a conversation.
그래서 대화를 시작할 때 그걸 염두에 두는 게 중요해요
The context window only needs to fit just the current prompt.
컨텍스트 창은 현재 프롬프트에만 맞으면 돼요
But as the conversation keeps going, it needs to be able to fit more and more of what's been said before,
하지만 대화가 계속될수록 전에 나온 내용과 더 잘 맞아떨어져야 해요
to be able to keep that context.
그 맥락을 유지하려면요
Um, and so this is particularly important in things like multi-shot prompting and so on.
이건 특히 멀티샷 프롬프트 같은 면에서 중요해요
And for example, if you wanted to ask a question about the complete works of Shakespeare, you would
예를 들어 셰익스피어 작품에 관해 질문하고 싶다면
need to have in the context window, the 1.2 million tokens all at one time.
컨텍스트 창 1을 눌러야 해요 한 번에 200만 토큰을 모으는 거죠
That's how it works.
그렇게 하는 거예요
So in a nutshell, that is the context window.
간단히 말하면 그게 컨텍스트 창이에요